<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Latest News | DES Research Unit</title><link>https://deslab.org/post/</link><atom:link href="https://deslab.org/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Latest News</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 07:00:52 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://deslab.org/media/logo_hu38ee6a744ccbfc031b9ab908dce502fd_20106_300x300_fit_lanczos_3.png</url><title>Latest News</title><link>https://deslab.org/post/</link></image><item><title>Montasser AKERMI Wins First Prize in In-Com Challenge</title><link>https://deslab.org/post/montasser-akermi-wins-first-prize-in-in-com-challenge/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 07:00:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://deslab.org/post/montasser-akermi-wins-first-prize-in-in-com-challenge/</guid><description>&lt;div style="text-align: justify">
We are proud to announce that our PhD researcher, Montasser AKERMI, has won first prize in the In-Com Challenge. The competition was held from March 2022 to March 2023, and Montasser's project was awarded first prize for its innovative approach to addressing Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs).&lt;/br>
Montasser's project aligned with SDG 8, SDG 9, SDG 12, and SDG 17. His team worked tirelessly to develop the project, and we are proud of their achievement.&lt;/br>
We congratulate Montasser on his winning entry and thank him for his dedication.
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Amina Amara PhD thesis defense</title><link>https://deslab.org/post/amina-amara-phd-thesis-defense/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 07:00:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://deslab.org/post/amina-amara-phd-thesis-defense/</guid><description>&lt;div style="text-align: justify">
&lt;b>Title:&lt;/b> A deep learning-based approach for anchor user modeling across online social networks under a big data environment. &lt;/br>
&lt;b>Supervisors:&lt;/b> Mohamed BEN AOUICHA &amp; Mohamed Ali HADJ TAEIB &lt;/br>
&lt;b>Defense Date:&lt;/b> 26 may 2022&lt;/br>
An accurate and comprehensive user modeling has been proven fundamental for many personalized social media-based services including link
prediction and recommendation systems. A major challenge lies in that data
available in a single online social network are usually very limited and
sparse. Depending on the purpose for which an online social platform is
designed, each platform offers only a partial view of a user from a particular
perspective. Therefore, users are usually involved in several online social
networks simultaneously to enjoy specific services provided by different
networks, thus bringing about the interconnection of online social networks
via bridge users called anchor users. Accordingly, a comprehensive anchor user
modeling requires taking into account the user’s social data scattered through
several social networking platforms. However, online social networks are
completely isolated. In this respect, the present research work aims to build
a holistic and comprehensive anchor user model from his data distributed over
multiple social information sources and thus serve for enhancing the quality
of personalized social media-based services. For this reason, we first study
different aspects related to the target social networking platforms selected
in this dissertation including covered functionalities, data heterogeneity,
and data accessibility. The study reveals also that the major challenge
towards anchor user modeling is linking user’s identities across online social
networks. Moreover, recent trend to solve the user modeling problem is to
leverage network embedding techniques and build embedding vectors
corresponding to user nodes in the social network. Thereby, this thesis
firstly presents a detailed survey of more recent network embedding based
approaches. Then, the problem of anchor user identification across social
platforms is addressed by providing a feature-based approach exploiting
various similarity measures. Indeed, the proposed algorithm leverages the
profile information (i.e. the user’s name) with the network properties (i.e.
friendship network) to compute the matching degree between the two user’s
identities pertaining to two different social networks and then the obtained
result is compared to a predefined threshold value to decide whether the two
profiles pertain to the same real person or not. Several similarity measures
are tested including Jaccard Index, Hub Promoted Index, Hub Depressed Index,
and Sørenson Index. Experimental results conducted on two real-world datasets,
collected from Facebook and Twitter social networks, showed that the Jaccard
Index outperforms all other measures with a threshold value δ = 0.03. In
addition, as social networks stand as typical sources of big data, a BIGUI
(BIG User Identification) architecture for anchor users storing and processing
is designed. The provided architecture is built on the basis of a set of
adequate technologies in conformity with the social big graph data pipeline to
cope with online social network-associated big data challenges. Thereafter,
the next step consists on building an anchor user model encoding diverse
network structures of the given user, i.e. intra-network and cross-network
features. In this regard, the OVRAU model (Overall low-dimensional Vector
Representation for Anchor Users) is implemented to learn an overall
low-dimensional representation for modeling anchor users, from a multiplex
heterogeneous social network, by investigating the intra-network as well as
cross-network structural information. Unlike existing works, the proposed
model considers the multi-network scenarios to capture diverse network
structures of anchor users. For this reason, OVRAU model includes two types of
embeddings for each anchor user: one high-dimensional base embedding and a
low-dimensional social edge embedding for each social network. In particular,
the model learns a function that generates social edge embeddings by sampling
and aggregating structural features from an anchor user's neighborhood inside
different social networks, through one of three candidate functions of
aggregation, namely mean aggregator, max-pooling aggregator, and LSTM
aggregator, with self-attention mechanism. Link prediction is used as a
downstream task to evaluate the effectiveness of the learned embeddings.
Experiments have been conducted on real-world social networks dataset and the
experimental results demonstrate that the proposed model with all three
variants can significantly outperform the existing approaches of network
representation learning when it is applied on link prediction task and also
achieves better performance over all compared baselines.
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Call for contribution to the research topic: Linked Open Bibliographic Data for Real-time Research Assessment</title><link>https://deslab.org/post/call-for-contribution-to-the-research-topic-linked-open-bibliographic-data-for-real-time-research-assessment/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 09:53:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://deslab.org/post/call-for-contribution-to-the-research-topic-linked-open-bibliographic-data-for-real-time-research-assessment/</guid><description>&lt;div style="text-align: justify">
Currently, large databases of open bibliographic metadata have been created and made available online in the age of open science. These resources are easily findable, accessible, interoperable, and reusable thanks to their online hosting and their representation as RDF (Resource Description Framework) knowledge graphs, and could be easily aligned together thanks to a set of unique identifiers such as ORCID ID, Wikidata ID, and DOI. The integration of heterogeneous bibliographic data such as author information (e.g., ORCID and DBLP), citations (e.g., OpenCitations and Crossref), research findings (e.g., ORKG), and the semantic knowledge about prizes, countries, research venues, publications and institutions (e.g., Wikidata) can be useful to develop high-level interpretations for the research assessment of entities.&lt;/br>
The structured format of RDF knowledge graphs can allow the automatic generation of real-time research evaluation outputs through the use of programming tools (e.g., APIs) and query services (e.g., SPARQL) as well as the enrichment and validation of bibliographic information through the use of machine learning, logical constraints, bibliometric-enhanced information retrieval, and shape expressions.&lt;/br>
In this themed article collection, we are keen to include original research, opinions, and application notes about the use of linked open bibliographic data for supporting timely research evaluation.
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Important Note&lt;/strong>: All contributions to this Research Topic must be within the scope of the section and journal to which they are submitted, as defined in their mission statements. Frontiers reserves the right to guide an out-of-scope manuscript to a more suitable section or journal at any stage of peer review.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="click-here-to-contributehttpswwwfrontiersinorgresearch-topics34449">&lt;a href="https://www.frontiersin.org/research-topics/34449" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Click here to contribute&lt;/a>&lt;/h2>
&lt;h2 id="submission-deadlines">Submission Deadlines&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Abstract&lt;/th>
&lt;th>&lt;strong>06 June 2022&lt;/strong>&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Manuscript&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>05 August 2022&lt;/strong>&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;!--EndFragment--></description></item></channel></rss>